"If I could only have one food to eat for the rest of my life?" "That's
easy. Pez. Cherry flavor Pez. No question about it."
Stand by Me is a crime, drama film directed by Rob Reiner.
After learning that a boy their age has been accidentally killed near
their rural homes, four boys decide to go see the body.
Gordie, Vern, Chris, and Teddy encounter a mean junk man and a marsh full of leeches, but
they also learn more about one another and their very different home lives.
Just a lark at first, the boys' adventure evolves
into a defining event in their lives.
Gordie Lachance, played by Wil Wheaton.
Chris Chambers, played by River Phoenix.
Teddy Duchamp, played by Corey Feldman.
Vern Tessio, played by Jerry O'Connell.
Ace Merrill, played by Kiefer Sutherland.
Billy Tessio, played by Casey Siemaszko.
Stand by Me is a 1986 American coming-of-age drama film directed by Rob Reiner.
Based on Stephen King's 1982 novella The Body, the film is set
in the fictional town of Castle Rock in 1959.
Stand by Me stars Wil Wheaton, River Phoenix, Corey Feldman, and Jerry O'Connell as four
boys who set out on a journey to find the dead body of a missing boy.
The film's title is derived from the 1961 song of the same name by Ben E.
King, which plays during the film's closing credits.
Released in the United States on August 22, 1986 by Columbia Pictures, Stand
by Me received positive reviews and was a commercial success.
The film was nominated for an Academy Award for Best Adapted Screenplay and for two
Golden Globe Awards (Best Drama Motion Picture and Best Director).
Rolling Stone has called Stand by Me "a staple of youthful nostalgia" and
"the rare movie that necessarily gets better with time".
The film explores themes of friendship, based on novel
or book, leech, bullying, road trip.
The tone is emotional.